<?xml version="1.0" encoding="utf-8"?>
<rss version="2.0" xmlns:atom="http://www.w3.org/2005/Atom"><channel><title>Does not compute</title><link>http://tuxcanfly.me/</link><description></description><atom:link href="http://tuxcanfly.me/feeds/all.xml" rel="self"></atom:link><lastBuildDate>Tue, 03 Dec 2013 20:47:00 +0530</lastBuildDate><item><title>The Great Gatsby - F. Scott Fitzgerald</title><link>http://tuxcanfly.me/the-great-gatsby.html</link><description>&lt;div class="figure align-center"&gt;
&lt;a class="reference external image-reference" href="http://tuxcanfly.me/images/the-great-gatsby.jpg"&gt;&lt;img alt="Cover Art - The Great Gatsby" src="http://tuxcanfly.me/images/the-great-gatsby.jpg" /&gt;&lt;/a&gt;
&lt;p class="caption"&gt;Original Book Cover - The Great Gatsby&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;/div&gt;
&lt;div class="section" id="review"&gt;
&lt;h2&gt;Review:&lt;/h2&gt;
&lt;blockquote class="epigraph"&gt;
&lt;p&gt;Reserving judgements is a matter of infinite hope.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;Let us learn to show our friendship for a man when he is alive and not after he is dead&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p class="attribution"&gt;&amp;mdash;F. Scott Fitzgerald&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;/blockquote&gt;
&lt;p&gt;The Great Gatsby is a showcase of the upper-class American society of the early
20th century. It's a cautionary tale of how unbridled desire can be
devastating. If you've seen the movie American Beauty (or The Great Gatsby),
you will probably find this book very similar.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;Jay Gatsby is an intriguing character with a dark past and an extravagant
lifestyle. Nick, a young hard-working salesman is the narrator and Gatsby's
neighbor. Tom and Daisy are couple who are Nick's friends and live nearby.
Jordan Baker, a young woman, is Daisy's friend and Nick's girlfriend. The last
couple - George and Myrtle are living in an unhappy marriage. To make matters
worse, Tom is cheating on his wife with Myrtle and Gatsby is trying to get back
Daisy, who rejected him when he wasn't rich. The action starts to unroll when
one unfortunate day all their paths cross.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;The tale takes a jab at the concept of &amp;quot;American Dream&amp;quot; (or any one predefined
way of living, really). Gatsby is rumored to be a murderer as soon as people
realize how rich he is; Gatsby's &amp;quot;Oxford&amp;quot; qualification is called into question
when Tom confronts him - all subtle hints at the psyche of the characters.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;4/5 - Short and sweet tale about relationships, lust, and materialism.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;/div&gt;
</description><dc:creator xmlns:dc="http://purl.org/dc/elements/1.1/">Javed Khan</dc:creator><pubDate>Tue, 03 Dec 2013 20:47:00 +0530</pubDate><guid>tag:tuxcanfly.me,2013-12-03:the-great-gatsby.html</guid><category>classic</category><category>books</category></item><item><title>Before they are hanged - Joe Abercrombie</title><link>http://tuxcanfly.me/before-they-are-hanged.html</link><description>&lt;div class="figure align-center"&gt;
&lt;a class="reference external image-reference" href="http://tuxcanfly.me/images/before-they-are-hanged.jpg"&gt;&lt;img alt="Cover Art - Before they are hanged" src="http://tuxcanfly.me/images/before-they-are-hanged.jpg" /&gt;&lt;/a&gt;
&lt;/div&gt;
&lt;div class="section" id="review"&gt;
&lt;h2&gt;Review:&lt;/h2&gt;
&lt;blockquote class="epigraph"&gt;
&lt;p&gt;We should forgive our enemies, but not before they are hanged.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p class="attribution"&gt;&amp;mdash;Heinrich_Heine&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;/blockquote&gt;
&lt;blockquote class="epigraph"&gt;
&lt;p&gt;Honour, eh? What the hell is that anyway? Every man thinks it's something
different. You can't drink it. You can't fuck it. The more of it you have the
less good it does you, and if you've got none at all you don't miss it.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p class="attribution"&gt;&amp;mdash;Logan Ninefingers&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;/blockquote&gt;
&lt;p&gt;Before they are hanged is the second book in the First Law series and it
continues the enchanting stories of Glokta, Jezal, Logan and Ferro. The story
is as brutal and the humour is as sarcastic as ever.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;Glokta is assigned the impossible task of defending Dagoska from the Gurkish
and he's tempted with an offer from the mysterious bank Valint and Balk. What
will he do, and will become of Dagoska?&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;Bayaz and he's crew including Jezal, Ferro, Logan along with the annoying
Brother Longfoot embark on a mission to retreive &amp;quot;The Seed&amp;quot; - a nuclear
bomb-esque weapon. Will their adventurous journey to the End of the World
through the ruins of Aulchus bear fruit?&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;Major West is tasked with the daunting task of defending Angland against Bethod
and his powerful army of northmen. He's surprised with an unexpected alliance
from Logan's long lost gang of rowdies, but will they stand against Bethod and
his witch?&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;We see a change starting to grow in all the major characters - Jezal begins to
outgrow his vanity as he's rescued by Ferro and Logan; Logan and Ferro fall in
love - if it could be called that; Glokta shows his soft side as he forgives a
known traitor - Majester Aida instead of sticking her head on a spear as Arch
Lector Sult would have wanted it.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;A little philosophical rant by Bayaz on how a king should rule and the history
and re-telling of the rivarly between Juvens and Kanedius adds and keeps the
mystery alive.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;4/5 - nice read.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;/div&gt;
</description><dc:creator xmlns:dc="http://purl.org/dc/elements/1.1/">Javed Khan</dc:creator><pubDate>Wed, 20 Nov 2013 23:40:00 +0530</pubDate><guid>tag:tuxcanfly.me,2013-11-20:before-they-are-hanged.html</guid><category>fantasy</category><category>books</category></item><item><title>Last argument of kings - Joe Abercrombie</title><link>http://tuxcanfly.me/last-argument-of-kings.html</link><description>&lt;div class="figure align-center"&gt;
&lt;a class="reference external image-reference" href="|filename|/images/last-argument-of-kings"&gt;&lt;img alt="Cover Art - Last argument of kings" src="|filename|/images/last-argument-of-kings" /&gt;&lt;/a&gt;
&lt;/div&gt;
&lt;div class="section" id="review"&gt;
&lt;h2&gt;Review:&lt;/h2&gt;
&lt;blockquote class="epigraph"&gt;
&lt;p&gt;Truly, life is the misery we endure between disappointments&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p class="attribution"&gt;&amp;mdash;Glokta&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;/blockquote&gt;
&lt;p&gt;Last argument of kings is the third and last book in the First Law series and
it ends with an epic showdown of the war between the Union and Gurkish and
Bethod.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;Glokta returns from Dagoska and is surprised to be promoted to the role of
Superior. Now, his task is to uncover the mysterious death of the crown prince
and rig the elections to make sure Arch Lector Sult isn't embarrassed by the
soon to be elected King. As he investigates, he finds himself in a tough spot
as his beneficiary, the mysterious bank of Valint and Balk wants him to spy on
his master, the Arch Lector himself. Will Glokta's wish to die and get rid of
his miserable life be fulfilled at last?&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;Bayaz returns empty-handed from the End of the World, and spins up a plan to
make Jezal the new King. Jezal's journey from a low ranking, vain and spoilt
officer to the King is remarkable. But his happiness is soon ruined due to
Bayaz and his unhappy wife. Meanwhile, the Gurkish are closing in on the city
with huge armies. What will happen of the Union when Gurkish run over it?&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;Ferro finds the seed in the house of the Maker, and Bayaz use this to his
advantage against Mamun and his hundred words. The incidents in the house of
the Maker invovling Tolomei and Yulwei makes one suspicious about the honesty
and intentions of Bayaz. Are Khalul the prophet and Mamun indeed the righteous
ones?&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;Philosophically, the book seems to provoke moral nihilism - there is no good
and evil - only power.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;4/5 - a fitting epic end to the series.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;/div&gt;
</description><dc:creator xmlns:dc="http://purl.org/dc/elements/1.1/">Javed Khan</dc:creator><pubDate>Wed, 20 Nov 2013 23:40:00 +0530</pubDate><guid>tag:tuxcanfly.me,2013-11-20:last-argument-of-kings.html</guid><category>fantasy</category><category>books</category></item><item><title>The Blade Itself - Joe Abercrombie</title><link>http://tuxcanfly.me/the-blade-itself.html</link><description>&lt;div class="figure align-center"&gt;
&lt;a class="reference external image-reference" href="http://tuxcanfly.me/images/the-blade-itself.jpg"&gt;&lt;img alt="Cover Art - The Blade Itself" src="http://tuxcanfly.me/images/the-blade-itself.jpg" /&gt;&lt;/a&gt;
&lt;/div&gt;
&lt;div class="section" id="review"&gt;
&lt;h2&gt;Review:&lt;/h2&gt;
&lt;blockquote class="epigraph"&gt;
&lt;p&gt;Shit&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p class="attribution"&gt;&amp;mdash;Almost everyone in this book&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;/blockquote&gt;
&lt;blockquote class="epigraph"&gt;
&lt;p&gt;Once you've got a task to do, it's better to do it than live with the fear of it.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p class="attribution"&gt;&amp;mdash;Logen Ninefingers&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;/blockquote&gt;
&lt;p&gt;The Blade Itself is the first book in the First Law series and it prepares the
ground for an epic battle.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;Reading the book is like immersing yourself in it's universe and watching the
characters in God Mode. Hands down, it has the best narrative I've ever read.
The characters feel so real, you just almost touch them. Every scene in the
book is vividly imprinted in the reader's memory in exquisite detail. This is
one of the few books that I enjoyed reading all the way, enjoyed more than
anticipation for the end.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;Overall the story itself is simple, it's laying down the groundwork for a
battle - an epic battle between the Union, Bethod, the Gurkish and various
other factions; but the narrative builds up so slowly and vividly that it
catches you by surprise when all the blocks fall into place.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;Glokta, a cripple, was a Prisoner-of-War who was tortured and returned to the
union.  Now he's the Inquisitor who tortures other people, pointlessly (or
fun, who knows?) One of his adventures with one Salem Rews, gets out of control
as everyone from the Supervisor Kaline to the Arch Lector Sult wants to use
Rews to sign off a confession for them. Glokta later realizes that he himself
was being played upon by the Arch Lector.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;Jezal dan Luthar is a young man, one would probably call him the hero of this
book, who is training to fight a fencing match championship. He falls in love
with his friend Major West's sister Ardi and some amusing events follow.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;Logen Ninefingers is a savage, brutal, primitive northman who has escaped the
Shanka (like Orcs) and on his way to find the first of the twelve Magi, Bayaz.
After meeting Bayaz, they reach the union where their paths cross Glokta's and
Luthar's.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;Ferro Maljinn, a fierce, ex-slave girl and the Magus Yulwei cross the Gurkish
badlands to come over to the union as a part of a bigger plan between the magi.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;On a very high level, the book is reminiscent of the Fellowship of the Ring i.e.
a rendezvous of the good guys preparing for a battle.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;On a philosophical level, I can't help but notice the parallels between the
myths of Juvens and Biblical stories. Even without reading too much into it,
Juvens and Kanedius' rivarly reminds us of Caine and Abel. Juvens himself
feels similar to Jesus, with twelve followers, one of whom is the betrayer
(Khalul). Juvens' Laws are similar to the Ten Commandments. The argument
between Bayaz and Yulwei regarding the First Law is the classic debate of
Consequentialism vs Deontology.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;/div&gt;
</description><dc:creator xmlns:dc="http://purl.org/dc/elements/1.1/">Javed Khan</dc:creator><pubDate>Wed, 20 Nov 2013 23:40:00 +0530</pubDate><guid>tag:tuxcanfly.me,2013-11-20:the-blade-itself.html</guid><category>fantasy</category><category>books</category></item><item><title>Lirael &amp; Abhorsen - Garth Nix</title><link>http://tuxcanfly.me/lirael-abhorsen.html</link><description>&lt;div class="section" id="review"&gt;
&lt;h2&gt;Review:&lt;/h2&gt;
&lt;blockquote class="epigraph"&gt;
&lt;p&gt;It's always better to be doing [than to live with the fear]&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p class="attribution"&gt;&amp;mdash;Garth Nix&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;/blockquote&gt;
&lt;p&gt;This is a combined review for both Lirael and Abhorsen since they are the
continuation of Sabriel in the Old Kingdom trilogy.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;/div&gt;
&lt;div class="section" id="lirael"&gt;
&lt;h2&gt;Lirael:&lt;/h2&gt;
&lt;div class="figure align-center"&gt;
&lt;a class="reference external image-reference" href="http://tuxcanfly.me/images/lirael.jpg"&gt;&lt;img alt="Cover Art - Lirael" src="http://tuxcanfly.me/images/lirael.jpg" /&gt;&lt;/a&gt;
&lt;/div&gt;
&lt;p&gt;Lirael starts off with the sob story of a young girl supposedly the daughter of
the Clayr (plural - some sort of Oracle). She is impatient about the Sight - a
gift of the Clayr which is denied to her even though she has grown up. As an
awkward, shy and depressed character, Lirael evokes some sympathy, but the
self-loathing gets a bit tiring after a while. She eventually gets a job in a
library and is drawn into an adventure where she finds a dog statue which she
brings to life using magic. The dog - called the Disreputable Dog is similar to
the cat Mogget in some aspects. Meanwhile, we meet Sameth, son of Sabriel who
is supposedly the Abhorsen in waiting, filling in his mother's shoes in
Ancelstierre. The rest of the book explains how Lirael and Sameth find
themselves drawn to an epic battle against Hedge - the rogue necromancer.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;/div&gt;
&lt;div class="section" id="abhorsen"&gt;
&lt;h2&gt;Abhorsen:&lt;/h2&gt;
&lt;div class="figure align-center"&gt;
&lt;a class="reference external image-reference" href="http://tuxcanfly.me/images/abhorsen.jpg"&gt;&lt;img alt="Cover Art - Abhorsen" src="http://tuxcanfly.me/images/abhorsen.jpg" /&gt;&lt;/a&gt;
&lt;/div&gt;
&lt;p&gt;Abhorsen is the final book in the trilogy and it explains some of the mysteries
about the magical world of Old Kingdom. Lirael, Sameth, Mogget and the
Disreputable Dog start off toward the Red Lake to stop the magical evil
hemi-spheres from combining and re-incarnating the Destroyer. Will they be able
to stop the Destroyer from coming back to life and destroying everything?
Let's just say that answer might not be surprising...&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;Questions about Mogget and the Disreputable Dog's origins are explained,
although somewhat shallowly. Maybe I was expecting too much, but I was waiting
for an &amp;quot;AHA!&amp;quot; moment which will enlighten me about the hidden meaning and some
philosophy of Death (or the lack thereof), but I had to remain contended with
the action.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;Overall I think the trilogy was aimed at a younger audience than me, so I guess
I couldn't enjoy it as much. If I had read it 5-6 years ago, I would have
probably liked it better.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;A good read for time-pass but so-so otherwise - 3.5/5.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;/div&gt;
</description><dc:creator xmlns:dc="http://purl.org/dc/elements/1.1/">Javed Khan</dc:creator><pubDate>Wed, 20 Nov 2013 22:40:00 +0530</pubDate><guid>tag:tuxcanfly.me,2013-11-20:lirael-abhorsen.html</guid><category>fantasy</category><category>books</category></item><item><title>Animal Farm - George Orwell</title><link>http://tuxcanfly.me/animal-farm.html</link><description>&lt;div class="figure align-center"&gt;
&lt;a class="reference external image-reference" href="http://tuxcanfly.me/images/animal-farm.jpg"&gt;&lt;img alt="Cover Art - Animal Farm" src="http://tuxcanfly.me/images/animal-farm.jpg" /&gt;&lt;/a&gt;
&lt;p class="caption"&gt;Original Book Cover - Animal Farm&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;/div&gt;
&lt;div class="section" id="review"&gt;
&lt;h2&gt;Review:&lt;/h2&gt;
&lt;blockquote class="epigraph"&gt;
&lt;p&gt;All animals are equal, but some animals are more equal than others.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;If you want a vision of the future, imagine a boot stamping on a human face
- forever.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p class="attribution"&gt;&amp;mdash;George Orwell&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;/blockquote&gt;
&lt;p&gt;Animal Farm is a short book by George Orwell but don't let it's small size and
cheerful title fool you because this is not a fairy tale. It's a cautionary
warning to all future generations about human nature - greed, narcissism, power
and corruption. Orwell had a unique insight into the psychology of various
sections of the society with relationship to their leaders and brilliantly
portrays them as different animals in the farm. If you haven't already, do
yourself a favor and read this book. It won't take more than a day to finish
it.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;The story starts off with a rebellion by all animals united against a common
enemy: Mr Jones, the farm owner. Two pigs - Snowball and Napoleon hatch a plan
and together with the support of horses, dogs, geese and all animals, are
successful in driving the farmer out. Rejoicing at the revolution, they set out
to re-create their society and write their own version of the sacred
commandments. The pigs being the most intelligent animals and the only
literate ones, are the authors of most of these laws. They soon realize their
privileged status and thus begin to hijack the revolution. Snowball wants to
create a windmill but is driven out because Napoleon has other plans and is
able to convince the animals the Snowball is actually a spy. Now Napoleon takes
over and the rest of the story details how greed and corruption turn him into
the very thing that all animals had revolted against - human.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;The metaphorical relation between different animals and different sections of
the public is very beautiful: pigs - intelligentsia, dogs - loyalists, sheep -
masses, horses - hard workers, raven - religious, donkey - old and wise. The
transformation of the pigs from revolutionaries to brutal dictators is also
worth noticing. It indicates that power corrupts everyone, however clean they
may appear today. Orwell also points out the distinct features of
Authoritarianism as it gradually begins to form - guilt-based witch-hunts, no
fair trials, brutal punishments, lies and propaganda, fear-mongering (Jones
will come back!, Snowball destroyed the windmill!), silently re-writing laws,
mind-numbing praises (Dear Leader, Comrade Napoleon), chants (Four legs good,
two legs bad!), songs, slogans, rituals; and suppression of thought.
Anti-authoritarian also means anti-religious since God is the ultimate
authority and the parallels between the farm under Napoleon and a Church or
Mosque are as plain as daylight.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;5/5 - Small and delightfully thought-provoking. Must-read.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;/div&gt;
</description><dc:creator xmlns:dc="http://purl.org/dc/elements/1.1/">Javed Khan</dc:creator><pubDate>Sat, 26 Oct 2013 22:00:00 +0530</pubDate><guid>tag:tuxcanfly.me,2013-10-26:animal-farm.html</guid><category>orwell</category><category>books</category></item><item><title>Kafka on the shore - Haruki Murakami</title><link>http://tuxcanfly.me/kafka-on-the-shore.html</link><description>&lt;div class="figure align-center"&gt;
&lt;a class="reference external image-reference" href="http://tuxcanfly.me/images/kafka-on-the-shore.jpg"&gt;&lt;img alt="Cover Art - Kafka on the shore" src="http://tuxcanfly.me/images/kafka-on-the-shore.jpg" /&gt;&lt;/a&gt;
&lt;p class="caption"&gt;Original Book Cover - Kafka on the shore&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;/div&gt;
&lt;div class="section" id="review"&gt;
&lt;h2&gt;Review:&lt;/h2&gt;
&lt;blockquote class="epigraph"&gt;
&lt;p&gt;Yeah, but if you look at it like that we're all pretty much empty, don't
you think?  You eat, take a dump, do your crummy job for your lousy pay,
and get laid occasionally, if you're lucky. What else is there?&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p class="attribution"&gt;&amp;mdash;Haruki Murakami, Kafka on the shore&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;/blockquote&gt;
&lt;p&gt;This is my first Murakami book and I didn't know what to expect. Boy, was I in
for a treat. Kafka's bizzare universe seems to have been waiting for someone to
revive it and Murakami sure looks like a worthy contender. Just like Kafka,
Murakami succeeds in conjuring up a world where things are slightly off and
there's obvious doom awaiting the protagonist. But, Murakami takes it further
and gives it a post-modern touch by adding elements of metaphors, magic,
philosophy and self-references.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;Kafka on the shore begins with a boy called Kafka packing his things and
preparing to run away from his home. He succeeds in reaching another place,
finding a place to live and thus evades the destiny that was awaiting him. Or
has he? He's living at a library with two peculiar characters - a transgender
man called Oshima and his(her?) loner boss called Miss Saeki. Meanwhile back in
Nakano (where Kafka runs away from), we're introduced to a mentally challenged
old man named Nakata who is gifted with the ability to talk to cats. The rest
of the story is all about how Kafka and Nakata's paths slowly but eventually
cross. A curse has been placed on Kafka by his father because of his mother's
sudden departure. Much as Kafka tries to avoid this curse, he seems to stumble
right in the middle of it.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;Fish raining from the sky, Johnnie Walker - the cat eater, Colonel Sanders - the
pimp, the philosophy grad hooker who talks Hegel, the ghost girl, the Entrance
Stone, the Edge of the World, the runaway soldiers. Sounds interesting, right?&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;If I had to condense the meaning I took from the book into one word, it would
be 'Acceptance'. Life is full of sadness - Miss Saeki's lover is brutally
murdered by a mob, Kafka's mother leaves without a word, Oshima is born woman
but lives as a man, Nakata had an accident which turns him into an Idiot; but
we shouldn't cling to these memories, we should put them behind and live - live
and enjoy. There's no point in worrying about the future as well - what's gonna
happen is gonna happen - like with Kafka, we can try and hide from fate, but we
can't avoid it. So we have to accept whatever comes our way, with a smile.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;Life's shit, so what?&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;5/5 - excellent read, might change your perspective on life.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;/div&gt;
</description><dc:creator xmlns:dc="http://purl.org/dc/elements/1.1/">Javed Khan</dc:creator><pubDate>Sat, 19 Oct 2013 22:00:00 +0530</pubDate><guid>tag:tuxcanfly.me,2013-10-19:kafka-on-the-shore.html</guid><category>kafka</category><category>books</category></item><item><title>Sabriel - Garth Nix</title><link>http://tuxcanfly.me/sabriel.html</link><description>&lt;div class="figure align-center"&gt;
&lt;a class="reference external image-reference" href="http://tuxcanfly.me/images/sabriel-book-cover.jpg"&gt;&lt;img alt="Cover Art - Sabriel" src="http://tuxcanfly.me/images/sabriel-book-cover.jpg" /&gt;&lt;/a&gt;
&lt;p class="caption"&gt;Original Book Cover - Sabriel&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;/div&gt;
&lt;div class="section" id="review"&gt;
&lt;h2&gt;Review:&lt;/h2&gt;
&lt;blockquote class="epigraph"&gt;
&lt;p&gt;Does the walker choose the path, or the path the walker?&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p class="attribution"&gt;&amp;mdash;Garth Nix, Sabriel&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;/blockquote&gt;
&lt;p&gt;Sabriel is the first book of the Old Kingdom aka the Abhorsen trilogy.  It's a
story about the coming-of-age of a young girl named Sabriel (surprise!).  The
plot is set somewhere in England in a place where the normal and the magical
worlds are divided by the Wall. Sabriel and other members of her family are the
Abhorsens or necromancers who are tasked with keeping the dead actually
dead and not letting them wander out into our living world. Death is the main theme
of the book and is described as another universe where dead souls float away in
a river and cross the various gates. Sabriel's adventure begins when she finds
out that her father has been trapped in one of these gates by the evil
Kerrigor. There are some touching father-daughter moments concerning death.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;The narrative is gripping and keeps your attention, but the plot is unoriginal
and a bit too melodramatic. Hardcore fantasy fans might also be disappointed by
the lack of details and history of the magical elements.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;Somewhat off topic, but the cover-art alone is worth buying this book! The
calm, yet determined expression of Sabriel, with her dark hair melting into the
dark realm of Death, it quite perfectly captures the essence of the story.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;3.5/5 - Overall a good read with some memorable if stereotyped characters.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;/div&gt;
</description><dc:creator xmlns:dc="http://purl.org/dc/elements/1.1/">Javed Khan</dc:creator><pubDate>Sun, 13 Oct 2013 16:00:00 +0530</pubDate><guid>tag:tuxcanfly.me,2013-10-13:sabriel.html</guid><category>sabriel</category><category>fantasy</category><category>books</category></item><item><title>His Dark Materials - Phillip Pullman</title><link>http://tuxcanfly.me/his-dark-materials.html</link><description>&lt;div class="section" id="review"&gt;
&lt;h2&gt;Review:&lt;/h2&gt;
&lt;div class="figure align-center"&gt;
&lt;a class="reference external image-reference" href="http://tuxcanfly.me/images/paradise-lost.jpg"&gt;&lt;img alt="The fall of Luciferìì" src="http://tuxcanfly.me/images/paradise-lost.jpg" /&gt;&lt;/a&gt;
&lt;p class="caption"&gt;Gustave Doré, The fall of Luciferìì. Illustration for John Milton’s
“Paradise Lost“ by Gustave Doré, 1866. License: Public Domain&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;/div&gt;
&lt;blockquote class="epigraph"&gt;
&lt;p&gt;We have to be all those difficult things like cheerful and kind and curious and
patient, and we’ve got to study and think and work hard, all of us, in all our
different worlds, and then we’ll build…&amp;quot; ... &amp;quot;And then what?&amp;quot; said her Dæmon
sleepily &amp;quot;build what?&amp;quot; &amp;quot;The Republic of Heaven.&amp;quot;&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p class="attribution"&gt;&amp;mdash;Chapter 37 The Botanic Garden, Amber Spyglass&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;/blockquote&gt;
&lt;p&gt;It's been about a week since I've finished the last chapter of the series, and
I'm still absolutely floored at what a magnificent journey it has been and
still reeling from the emotional roller-coaster that the last chapters have
been. The series starts of with so many open mysteries and ends them all with
such grace that you can only wonder at it in awe. I'm glad that such a series
exists, that I came to know about it and had the extremely grateful opportunity
to read and enjoy it. I'm a mere mortal and I'm sure I can't do this series
justice by reviewing it, but I shall dare to try anyway.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;His Dark Materials is an epic fantasy trilogy consisting of three books:&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;ul class="simple"&gt;
&lt;li&gt;The Northern Lights&lt;/li&gt;
&lt;li&gt;The Subtle Knife&lt;/li&gt;
&lt;li&gt;The Amber Spyglass&lt;/li&gt;
&lt;/ul&gt;
&lt;div class="section" id="the-northern-lights"&gt;
&lt;h3&gt;The Northern Lights:&lt;/h3&gt;
&lt;p&gt;The story is set in a parallel universe not unlike ours (although in the
beginning of the modern age), but with Dust, dæmons, the Alethiometer, witches,
angels and armoured bears. Lyra and her dæmon, Pantalaimon are off to a great
adventure to the North with the Gyptians where they'll need to rescue children
who have been kidnapped by the Gobblers. On her journey, Lyra encounters the
witches and armoured bears, seeking their help in her task. With courage,
cunning and the help of Iorek Byrnison the armoured bear, she takes on the evil
Gobblers. Towards the end, she has to choose between staying back or following
her father into another universe to seek closure for a friend she betrays
accidentally.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;The action, adventure and mystery in this book make for a gripping narrative
will keep the reader hooked to solve the puzzle. A brief chat between the witch
Serafina Pekkala and the aeronaut Lee Scoresby contrasts the politics of both
sides. The exchange of words between Lyra and her father towards the end throws
light on the book's philosophy.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;/div&gt;
&lt;div class="section" id="the-subtle-knife"&gt;
&lt;h3&gt;The Subtle Knife:&lt;/h3&gt;
&lt;p&gt;Finding herself in a strange new world (Cittàgazze), Lyra wanders and finds
another visitor, Will (from our current universe) and thus begins another
adventure to find Will's father, John Parry who is believed to have travelled
across to another universe. They enter Will's universe and find themselves in
trouble because the Alethiometer gets stolen by one of the members of the
Church and they have to find a certain &amp;quot;Subtle Knife&amp;quot; to get their Alethiometer
back. After a long fight with Knife's owner in Cittàgazze, they manage to get
hold of it and soon discover it's magic - it's a knife that can cut through the
very fabric of time and space to create a portal into another Universe! So, the
children use it and get back their stolen stuff with a clever plan. Lyra also
makes a new friend called Dr Mary Malone whose research into Dark Matter turns
out be similar to Dust. Meanwhile, Lyra's old friend Mr. Scoresby is assisting
Will's father find the children. Unfortunately, also looking for Will and Lyra
is a unit of the Church, headed by Mrs Coulter.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;The second book introduces elements of science-fiction and builds on the
growing tension between the freethinkers headed by Lord Asriel and the Church.
There are a few heartbreaking moments when Lee Scoresby defends against the
Church's army and John Parry meets his son, Will.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;/div&gt;
&lt;div class="section" id="the-amber-spyglass"&gt;
&lt;h3&gt;The Amber Spyglass:&lt;/h3&gt;
&lt;p&gt;We find that Mrs Coulter has kidnapped Lyra and many groups are looking for her
including Will and the armoured bears whom he befriends, Lord Asriel's army and
the Church's army. As is expected, there's a showdown between the three forces,
and the children manage to escape to another universe, Mrs Coulter is captured
by Lord Asriel's army. Meanwhile, Dr Mary Malone crosses into a strange
universe with small elephant-like creatures using wheels in addition to their
limbs. As the children go looking for the world of the dead, we find that the
Church has dispatched a hitman to kill Lyra to prevent a prophecy which would
end the Church's power. Mrs Coulter escapes to the Church, spies on them and
learns of another plan to assasinate Lyra. With the introduction of Metatron,
the Authority's commander, the fate of the battle between Lord Asriel and all
of the Church looms in the balance.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;After an epic battle, we find the children with Dr Mary Malone who tempts them
into falling in love by telling them her story. What follows is an absolutely
amazing sequence recreating the traditional Adam and Eve story - the
temptation, the fall, the realization and acceptance.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;/div&gt;
&lt;/div&gt;
&lt;div class="section" id="conclusion"&gt;
&lt;h2&gt;Conclusion:&lt;/h2&gt;
&lt;p&gt;There are lot of fantasy books and lots of beautiful poems, but in my opinion
none can match the breathtaking mix of fantasy and poetry that is His Dark
Materials. Yes, there are a few loose threads, but I think they are far too
minor to worry about. To crave for a 'happy lived together ever after' ending
is to miss the point of the book - there's no Paradise after all! If you want
one, create it yourself!&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;/div&gt;
</description><dc:creator xmlns:dc="http://purl.org/dc/elements/1.1/">Javed Khan</dc:creator><pubDate>Sun, 06 Oct 2013 16:00:00 +0530</pubDate><guid>tag:tuxcanfly.me,2013-10-06:his-dark-materials.html</guid><category>his-dark-materials</category><category>fantasy</category><category>books</category></item><item><title>The Trial - Franz Kafka</title><link>http://tuxcanfly.me/the-trial.html</link><description>&lt;div class="section" id="review"&gt;
&lt;h2&gt;Review:&lt;/h2&gt;
&lt;p&gt;The Trial is a wonderful yet depressing book by Franz Kafka which explores the
human condition while telling the story about a mysterious trial endured by a
certain Mr Joseph K who works as a Chief Clerk in a bank.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;One day, Mr K is surprised to find Police in his home, who are there to arrest
him for a crime which they can't reveal - because it's secret. Now, he is faced
with the daunting task of preparing his defence, without knowing any details
about the accusations, or hearing any arguments from the prosecution. Secret
courts, shabby courtrooms located in attics, strange lawyers and even stranger
laws all contribute to the madness that Mr K has to deal with.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;The book plays on the theme of the Condemned Man -  similar to other
existentialist literature like Crime and Punishment by Dostoyevsky and The
Outsider by Albert Camus, but is much more enjoyable because of the bizarre,
crazy and sadistic bureaucracy involved in the courtroom. Subtle allegories
point toward the similarities between the human condition and Mr K's plight.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;4/5 - a pleasure to read.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;/div&gt;
</description><dc:creator xmlns:dc="http://purl.org/dc/elements/1.1/">Javed Khan</dc:creator><pubDate>Mon, 08 Jul 2013 23:00:00 +0530</pubDate><guid>tag:tuxcanfly.me,2013-07-08:the-trial.html</guid><category>kafka</category><category>books</category></item><item><title>The Metamorphosis - Franz Kafka</title><link>http://tuxcanfly.me/the-metamorphosis.html</link><description>&lt;div class="section" id="review"&gt;
&lt;h2&gt;Review:&lt;/h2&gt;
&lt;p&gt;The Metamorphosis (Die Verwandlung) is a novella by Franz Kafka which tells a
bizarre story with a rather mundane conclusion. It's surreal premise and
claustrophobic environment keeps the reader guessing throughout.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;The story is set in an early 20th century Germany city and takes place in the
household of the Mr and Mrs. Samsa who live with their son and daughter -
Gregory and Grete.  Gregory is a hard-working salesman who supports his family,
while the rest of the family members are dependent on him. So far, so good. Now
one fine day, Gregory turns into a weird human-sized bug and what follows is
the turn of events that occur in their household and how Gregory copes with his
newfound cockroach-like body. Doesn't make sense? Well.. too bad for you.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;Now that Mr. Gregory, the cockroach, is incapable of supporting the family,
it's up to his parents and his sister to provide for themselves and also take
care of him. At the end of the story, the sister is shown to have matured and
the parents also seem to have regained their health. I guess the question is -
what was the metamorphosis and what changed?&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;Warning! - The answer might trigger an existential crisis.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;4/5 - would read again&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;/div&gt;
</description><dc:creator xmlns:dc="http://purl.org/dc/elements/1.1/">Javed Khan</dc:creator><pubDate>Wed, 26 Jun 2013 22:00:00 +0530</pubDate><guid>tag:tuxcanfly.me,2013-06-26:the-metamorphosis.html</guid><category>kafka</category><category>books</category></item><item><title>Bitcoin for developers</title><link>http://tuxcanfly.me/bitcoin-for-developers.html</link><description>&lt;div class="section" id="about"&gt;
&lt;h2&gt;About&lt;/h2&gt;
&lt;p&gt;This was a talk on Bitcoin I presented at Agiliq - April 2013&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;div style="height:60%; width:60%"&gt;
    &lt;script async class="speakerdeck-embed" data-id="5350f0707f4001303c5e22000a1d8ce4" data-ratio="1.33333333333333" src="http://speakerdeck.com/assets/embed.js"&gt;&lt;/script&gt;
&lt;/div&gt;&lt;/div&gt;
</description><dc:creator xmlns:dc="http://purl.org/dc/elements/1.1/">Javed Khan</dc:creator><pubDate>Sun, 05 May 2013 22:00:00 +0530</pubDate><guid>tag:tuxcanfly.me,2013-05-05:bitcoin-for-developers.html</guid><category>bitcoin</category><category>talk</category></item><item><title>Month of FOSS contributions - Apr '13</title><link>http://tuxcanfly.me/month-of-foss-contributions-apr-13.html</link><description>&lt;div class="section" id="about"&gt;
&lt;h2&gt;About&lt;/h2&gt;
&lt;p&gt;Stuff that I contributed to Open Source in Apr '13.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;/div&gt;
&lt;div class="section" id="merchant"&gt;
&lt;h2&gt;Merchant&lt;/h2&gt;
&lt;p&gt;django-merchant is a Django app to accept payments from various payment
processors via Pluggable backends.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;I'm glad to have the chance the contribute to merchant again; I was previously
involved in the design as well as eWay and bitcoin backends.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;I have added a Continuous Integration build for merchant over at &lt;a class="reference external" href="https://travis-ci.org/agiliq/merchant"&gt;Travis&lt;/a&gt;&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;What's more, the &lt;a class="reference external" href="http://merchant.agiliq.com"&gt;demo&lt;/a&gt; is less of an eyesore now; it has been revamped using
bootstrap&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;We received contributions to Braintree, Google Checkout, and eWay backends
which I have reviewed and merged.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;Overall, it’s been a really good month for django-merchant, here's to hoping
this continues.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;div class="figure align-center"&gt;
&lt;a class="reference external image-reference" href="http://tuxcanfly.me/images/merchant-progress.png"&gt;&lt;img alt="Merchant Progress" src="http://tuxcanfly.me/images/merchant-progress.png" /&gt;&lt;/a&gt;
&lt;p class="caption"&gt;GitHub pulse for django-merchant&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;/div&gt;
&lt;/div&gt;
</description><dc:creator xmlns:dc="http://purl.org/dc/elements/1.1/">Javed Khan</dc:creator><pubDate>Sun, 05 May 2013 21:00:00 +0530</pubDate><guid>tag:tuxcanfly.me,2013-05-05:month-of-foss-contributions-apr-13.html</guid><category>foss</category><category>contributions</category></item><item><title>Month of FOSS contributions - Mar '13</title><link>http://tuxcanfly.me/month-of-foss-contributions-mar-13.html</link><description>&lt;div class="section" id="about"&gt;
&lt;h2&gt;About&lt;/h2&gt;
&lt;p&gt;Stuff that I contributed to Open Source in Mar '13.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;/div&gt;
&lt;div class="section" id="django"&gt;
&lt;h2&gt;Django&lt;/h2&gt;
&lt;p&gt;I debugged an issue in django &lt;cite&gt;ModelChoiceField&lt;/cite&gt; and &lt;cite&gt;ModelMultipleChoiceField&lt;/cite&gt;
which was causing model forms to be validated even though they weren't changed.
The problem was that &lt;cite&gt;has_changed&lt;/cite&gt; was comparing an &lt;cite&gt;object_id&lt;/cite&gt; or list of
&lt;cite&gt;ids&lt;/cite&gt; with an instance or queryset.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;Even though the fix was a part of another branch, the tests I had proposed were
included in the commit.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;&lt;a class="reference external" href="https://github.com/django/django/commit/3318595c0bfeda9f6bae8aa11dda68647ae55fde"&gt;3318595c&lt;/a&gt;&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;&lt;a class="reference external" href="https://github.com/django/django/pull/660"&gt;Pull request&lt;/a&gt;&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;/div&gt;
&lt;div class="section" id="vimux-django-tests"&gt;
&lt;h2&gt;Vimux-django-tests&lt;/h2&gt;
&lt;p&gt;This is a pet project that I started to make it easier to run individual django
tests from within vim.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;&lt;a class="reference external" href="https://github.com/tuxcanfly/vimux-django-tests"&gt;Vimux-django-tests&lt;/a&gt;&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;/div&gt;
</description><dc:creator xmlns:dc="http://purl.org/dc/elements/1.1/">Javed Khan</dc:creator><pubDate>Sun, 31 Mar 2013 21:00:00 +0530</pubDate><guid>tag:tuxcanfly.me,2013-03-31:month-of-foss-contributions-mar-13.html</guid><category>foss</category><category>contributions</category></item><item><title>Logging in Django</title><link>http://tuxcanfly.me/logging-in-django.html</link><description>&lt;div class="section" id="about"&gt;
&lt;h2&gt;About&lt;/h2&gt;
&lt;p&gt;This was a talk I presented at Hyderbad Python meetup - March 2013&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;div style="height:60%; width:60%"&gt;
    &lt;script async class="speakerdeck-embed" data-id="b33f5e2074ec0130286a22000a1f8aa6" data-ratio="1.33333333333333" src="http://speakerdeck.com/assets/embed.js"&gt;&lt;/script&gt;
&lt;/div&gt;&lt;/div&gt;
</description><dc:creator xmlns:dc="http://purl.org/dc/elements/1.1/">Javed Khan</dc:creator><pubDate>Sat, 30 Mar 2013 17:00:00 +0530</pubDate><guid>tag:tuxcanfly.me,2013-03-30:logging-in-django.html</guid><category>django</category><category>talk</category></item><item><title>Month of FOSS contributions - Feb '13</title><link>http://tuxcanfly.me/month-of-foss-contributions-feb-13.html</link><description>&lt;div class="section" id="about"&gt;
&lt;h2&gt;About&lt;/h2&gt;
&lt;p&gt;I'm documenting my contributions to FOSS every month from now for two purposes:&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;ul class="simple"&gt;
&lt;li&gt;As a log of my activity&lt;/li&gt;
&lt;li&gt;To serve as a motivation for further participation&lt;/li&gt;
&lt;/ul&gt;
&lt;p&gt;Psst, also for boasting about it, wink wink.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;/div&gt;
&lt;div class="section" id="whoosh"&gt;
&lt;h2&gt;Whoosh&lt;/h2&gt;
&lt;p&gt;While trying to work on django-haystack, I found a bug reported by Zed Shaw
where a search query would crash the search page provided by haystack.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;Upon digging into haystack and whoosh, I found that there's a edge case in the
whoosh query parser where passing a query containg a stop word and negative
filter can raise an error (e.g: the query string &lt;cite&gt;?q=-1&lt;/cite&gt;). I figured out a simple
fix and submitted a pull request which was promptly accepted.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;I was hoping to find something to contribute to haystack and help with the
maintanance, but looks like it will have to wait untill I get some more time.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;&lt;a class="reference external" href="https://bitbucket.org/mchaput/whoosh/commits/362fc2999c8cabc51370f433de7402fafd536ec6"&gt;362fc299&lt;/a&gt;&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;/div&gt;
&lt;div class="section" id="django-browserid"&gt;
&lt;h2&gt;django-browserid&lt;/h2&gt;
&lt;p&gt;I have always been a fan of mozilla and django-browserid looks like the perfect
match for me to contribute towards. I tried out the library by going through
the docs and found it to be a breeze. I was able to improve the docs a bit and
triage a few bugs.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;I have to say people working on this project are very helpful and
understanding. Looking forward to spending more time on this project in the
future.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;&lt;a class="reference external" href="https://github.com/mozilla/django-browserid/commit/f5fc0f124fda1fded862863ef56cab11f23c308d"&gt;f5fc0f12&lt;/a&gt;&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;&lt;a class="reference external" href="https://github.com/mozilla/django-browserid/commit/b9a17a4088211908de2a17a57668a646555f068a"&gt;b9a17a408&lt;/a&gt;&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;/div&gt;
&lt;div class="section" id="conclusion"&gt;
&lt;h2&gt;Conclusion&lt;/h2&gt;
&lt;p&gt;I really enjoyed working on these projects, and I'm looking forward to speding more time to get more
comfortable with them and contributing even more. Here's to bigger, better things!&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;/div&gt;
</description><dc:creator xmlns:dc="http://purl.org/dc/elements/1.1/">Javed Khan</dc:creator><pubDate>Thu, 28 Feb 2013 21:00:00 +0530</pubDate><guid>tag:tuxcanfly.me,2013-02-28:month-of-foss-contributions-feb-13.html</guid><category>foss</category><category>contributions</category></item><item><title>Developing Ubuntu Apps for fun and profit</title><link>http://tuxcanfly.me/pycon-india-2012-talk.html</link><description>&lt;div class="section" id="about"&gt;
&lt;h2&gt;About&lt;/h2&gt;
&lt;p&gt;This was a talk I presented at PyCon India 2012.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;iframe src="https://docs.google.com/presentation/d/1FCkHcZ8cim0oy58sOcG7xeyL4HKmP4v8xR4_wdnLYxM/embed?start=false&amp;loop=false&amp;delayms=3000" frameborder="0" width="480" height="389" allowfullscreen="true" mozallowfullscreen="true" webkitallowfullscreen="true"&gt;&lt;/iframe&gt;&lt;/div&gt;
</description><dc:creator xmlns:dc="http://purl.org/dc/elements/1.1/">Javed Khan</dc:creator><pubDate>Sat, 23 Feb 2013 17:00:00 +0530</pubDate><guid>tag:tuxcanfly.me,2013-02-23:pycon-india-2012-talk.html</guid><category>ubuntu</category><category>talk</category></item><item><title>Announcing Editorize beta</title><link>http://tuxcanfly.me/announcing-editorize-beta.html</link><description>&lt;div class="section" id="summary"&gt;
&lt;h2&gt;Summary&lt;/h2&gt;
&lt;p&gt;Editorize summons up your favorite text editor with a global shortcut so that
you can edit your text the way you want it. Close the file and the text
automagically gets pasted in to the text field you were editing.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;Editorize is in beta and needs some bugfixes/cleanup before it can be
considered stable.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;/div&gt;
&lt;div class="section" id="installation"&gt;
&lt;h2&gt;Installation&lt;/h2&gt;
&lt;p&gt;The easiest way to install editorize is by &lt;a class="reference external" href="https://launchpad.net/~tuxcanfly/+archive/editorize"&gt;using the ppa&lt;/a&gt;:&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;div class="highlight"&gt;&lt;pre&gt;sudo apt-add-repository ppa:tuxcanfly/editorize
&lt;/pre&gt;&lt;/div&gt;
&lt;p&gt;After that, updated and install the &lt;cite&gt;editorize&lt;/cite&gt; package:&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;div class="highlight"&gt;&lt;pre&gt;sudo apt-get update
sudo apt-get install editorize
&lt;/pre&gt;&lt;/div&gt;
&lt;p&gt;Source packages are available from the &lt;a class="reference external" href="https://launchpad.net/editorize"&gt;launchpad project page&lt;/a&gt;.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;Now you should be able to launch the app from the start menu / dash or using
the command &lt;cite&gt;editorize&lt;/cite&gt;&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;/div&gt;
&lt;div class="section" id="usage"&gt;
&lt;h2&gt;Usage&lt;/h2&gt;
&lt;p&gt;The default global keyboard shortcut for launching your default text editor is:&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;div class="highlight"&gt;&lt;pre&gt;&amp;lt;Ctrl&amp;gt;&amp;lt;Alt&amp;gt;i
&lt;/pre&gt;&lt;/div&gt;
&lt;p&gt;Both the shortcut and text editor can be customized from the &lt;cite&gt;Preferences&lt;/cite&gt; menu
of the App Indicator.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;Just go to a text input field on any app and use the above keyboard shortcut
and your text editor should pop open. Now enter your text, save and close the
editor. The input text should get copied to the app.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;/div&gt;
&lt;div class="section" id="help-bugs"&gt;
&lt;h2&gt;Help/Bugs:&lt;/h2&gt;
&lt;p&gt;Please report &lt;a class="reference external" href="https://bugs.launchpad.net/editorize"&gt;bugs on launchpad&lt;/a&gt;&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;/div&gt;
</description><dc:creator xmlns:dc="http://purl.org/dc/elements/1.1/">Javed Khan</dc:creator><pubDate>Mon, 14 Jan 2013 17:00:00 +0530</pubDate><guid>tag:tuxcanfly.me,2013-01-14:announcing-editorize-beta.html</guid><category>ubuntu</category><category>editorize</category><category>project</category></item><item><title>Boost your productivity with compiz</title><link>http://tuxcanfly.me/compiz-productivity.html</link><description>&lt;div class="section" id="summary"&gt;
&lt;h2&gt;Summary&lt;/h2&gt;
&lt;p&gt;Compiz provides powerful window control features which can be used to improve
daily work flow.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;/div&gt;
&lt;div class="section" id="installation"&gt;
&lt;h2&gt;Installation&lt;/h2&gt;
&lt;p&gt;To start off, you'll need to install the following additional packages:&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;div class="highlight"&gt;&lt;pre&gt;compizconfig-settings-manager compiz-plugins-main compiz-plugins-extra
&lt;/pre&gt;&lt;/div&gt;
&lt;div class="warning"&gt;
&lt;p class="first admonition-title"&gt;Warning&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;Before you proceed, you should know that fiddling with compiz is risky and
will probably cause your desktop session to freeze if something goes wrong.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p class="last"&gt;&lt;a class="reference external" href="http://www.ubuntugeek.com/enable-ctrl-alt-backspace-in-ubuntukubuntu-10-04lucid-lynx.html"&gt;Enable XServer Zap&lt;/a&gt; keyboard shortcut and be prepared to use it.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;/div&gt;
&lt;/div&gt;
&lt;div class="section" id="preferences"&gt;
&lt;h2&gt;Preferences&lt;/h2&gt;
&lt;p&gt;Checkout the Preferences options. I prefer the Flat-file configuration backend
as I want to keep all my compiz configuration in a single file and version
control it.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;Make sure you create a backup of your current config using the Export option
before you start.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;Here's my &lt;a class="reference external" href="https://gist.github.com/4296914"&gt;compiz config&lt;/a&gt; if you want to import it.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;/div&gt;
&lt;div class="section" id="commands"&gt;
&lt;h2&gt;Commands&lt;/h2&gt;
&lt;div class="figure align-center"&gt;
&lt;a class="reference external image-reference" href="http://tuxcanfly.me/images/commands.gif"&gt;&lt;img alt="Showcasing compiz commands" src="http://tuxcanfly.me/images/commands.gif" /&gt;&lt;/a&gt;
&lt;p class="caption"&gt;I've mapped &amp;lt;Super&amp;gt;Return to my terminal (urxvt) and
&amp;lt;Super&amp;gt;e to my editor (gvim)&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;/div&gt;
&lt;p&gt;The Commands plugin gives you a simple way to assign keyboard shortcuts to any
command.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;Figure out your most used commands/apps and assign shortcuts to them. No more
wading your way through menus and searching for apps. Some commands I use:&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;div class="highlight"&gt;&lt;pre&gt;urxvt -&amp;gt; &amp;lt;Super&amp;gt;Return
gvim -&amp;gt; &amp;lt;Super&amp;gt;e
chromium-browser --incognito -&amp;gt; &amp;lt;Shift&amp;gt;&amp;lt;Super&amp;gt;w
nautilus -&amp;gt; &amp;lt;Super&amp;gt;t
gnome-screensaver-command --lock -&amp;gt; &amp;lt;Super&amp;gt;b
&lt;/pre&gt;&lt;/div&gt;
&lt;/div&gt;
&lt;div class="section" id="general"&gt;
&lt;h2&gt;General&lt;/h2&gt;
&lt;a class="reference external image-reference" href="http://tuxcanfly.me/images/general.gif"&gt;&lt;img alt="Showcasing general key bindings" class="align-center" src="http://tuxcanfly.me/images/general.gif" /&gt;&lt;/a&gt;
&lt;p&gt;I find the key-bindings in this section very useful. For example:&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;div class="highlight"&gt;&lt;pre&gt;Close Window -&amp;gt; &amp;lt;Super&amp;gt;q
Toggle Window Maximizes -&amp;gt; &amp;lt;Super&amp;gt;m
&lt;/pre&gt;&lt;/div&gt;
&lt;p&gt;Combined with Commands plugin above, this configuration allows you to spawn,
close and maximize/restore your windows all with key-bindings!&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;/div&gt;
&lt;div class="section" id="extra-wm-actions"&gt;
&lt;h2&gt;Extra WM Actions&lt;/h2&gt;
&lt;a class="reference external image-reference" href="http://tuxcanfly.me/images/extra.gif"&gt;&lt;img alt="Showcasing extra wm actions" class="align-center" src="http://tuxcanfly.me/images/extra.gif" /&gt;&lt;/a&gt;
&lt;p&gt;Ever wanted to turn a window fullscreen but couldn't because the app doesn't
allow it?  Want to keep a window on top?&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;Extra WM actions provides key-bindings for these features. The mapping I use:&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;div class="highlight"&gt;&lt;pre&gt;Toggle Fullscreen -&amp;gt; &amp;lt;Supfer&amp;gt;f
&lt;/pre&gt;&lt;/div&gt;
&lt;/div&gt;
&lt;div class="section" id="grid"&gt;
&lt;h2&gt;Grid&lt;/h2&gt;
&lt;a class="reference external image-reference" href="http://tuxcanfly.me/images/grid.gif"&gt;&lt;img alt="Showcasing grid plugin" class="align-center" src="http://tuxcanfly.me/images/grid.gif" /&gt;&lt;/a&gt;
&lt;p&gt;Grid provides a window tiling feature with intuitive key-bindings. It's great
for people coming from a tiling window manager (like me).&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;/div&gt;
&lt;div class="section" id="desktop-wall-cube"&gt;
&lt;h2&gt;Desktop Wall/Cube&lt;/h2&gt;
&lt;a class="reference external image-reference" href="http://tuxcanfly.me/images/desktops.gif"&gt;&lt;img alt="Showcasing desktop wall" class="align-center" src="http://tuxcanfly.me/images/desktops.gif" /&gt;&lt;/a&gt;
&lt;p&gt;Both plugins provide an intuitive UI for multiple workspaces and are very
helpful for multitasking.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;I map the Move Left/Right to keys on the home row:&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;div class="highlight"&gt;&lt;pre&gt;Move Left -&amp;gt; &amp;lt;Shift&amp;gt;&amp;lt;Control&amp;gt;&amp;lt;Primary&amp;gt;&amp;lt;Super&amp;gt;j
Move Right -&amp;gt; &amp;lt;Shift&amp;gt;&amp;lt;Control&amp;gt;&amp;lt;Primary&amp;gt;&amp;lt;Super&amp;gt;k
&lt;/pre&gt;&lt;/div&gt;
&lt;/div&gt;
&lt;div class="section" id="conclusion"&gt;
&lt;h2&gt;Conclusion&lt;/h2&gt;
&lt;p&gt;I find compiz's features and customizability very useful and I hope you do too.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;Let me know if you know any useful tips in comments.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;/div&gt;
</description><dc:creator xmlns:dc="http://purl.org/dc/elements/1.1/">Javed Khan</dc:creator><pubDate>Sat, 15 Dec 2012 17:00:00 +0530</pubDate><guid>tag:tuxcanfly.me,2012-12-15:compiz-productivity.html</guid><category>compiz</category></item></channel></rss>