<?xml version="1.0" encoding="utf-8"?>
<feed xmlns="http://www.w3.org/2005/Atom"><title>Does not compute</title><link href="http://tuxcanfly.me/" rel="alternate"></link><link href="http://tuxcanfly.me/feeds/all.atom.xml" rel="self"></link><id>http://tuxcanfly.me/</id><updated>2013-10-13T16:00:00+05:30</updated><entry><title>Sabriel - Garth Nix</title><link href="http://tuxcanfly.me/sabriel.html" rel="alternate"></link><updated>2013-10-13T16:00:00+05:30</updated><author><name>Javed Khan</name></author><id>tag:tuxcanfly.me,2013-10-13:sabriel.html</id><summary type="html">&lt;div class="figure align-center"&gt;
&lt;a class="reference external image-reference" href="http://tuxcanfly.me/static/images/sabriel-book-cover.jpg"&gt;&lt;img alt="Cover Art - Sabriel" src="http://tuxcanfly.me/static/images/sabriel-book-cover.jpg" /&gt;&lt;/a&gt;
&lt;p class="caption"&gt;Original Book Cover - Sabriel&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;/div&gt;
&lt;div class="section" id="review"&gt;
&lt;h2&gt;Review:&lt;/h2&gt;
&lt;p&gt;Quote:&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;pre class="literal-block"&gt;
&amp;quot;Does the walker choose the path, or the path the walker?”
― Garth Nix, Sabriel
&lt;/pre&gt;
&lt;p&gt;Sabriel is the first book of the Old Kingdom aka the Abhorsen trilogy.  It's a
story about the coming-of-age of a young girl named Sabriel (surprise!).  The
plot is set somewhere in England in a place where the normal and the magical
worlds are divided by the Wall. Sabriel and other members of her family are the
Abhorsens or necromancers who are tasked with keeping the dead actually
dead and not letting them wander out into our living world. Death is the main theme
of the book and is described as another universe where dead souls float away in
a river and cross the various gates. Sabriel's adventure begins when she finds
out that her father has been trapped in one of these gates by the evil
Kerrigor. There are some touching father-daughter moments concerning death.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;The narrative is gripping and keeps your attention, but the plot is unoriginal
and a bit too melodramatic. Hardcore fantasy fans might also be disappointed by
the lack of details and history of the magical elements.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;Somewhat off topic, but the cover-art alone is worth buying this book! The
calm, yet determined expression of Sabriel, with her dark hair melting into the
dark realm of Death, it quite perfectly captures the essence of the story.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;3.5/5 - Overall a good read with some memorable if stereotyped characters.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;/div&gt;
</summary><category term="sabriel"></category><category term="fantasy"></category><category term="books"></category></entry><entry><title>His Dark Materials - Phillip Pullman</title><link href="http://tuxcanfly.me/his-dark-materials.html" rel="alternate"></link><updated>2013-10-06T16:00:00+05:30</updated><author><name>Javed Khan</name></author><id>tag:tuxcanfly.me,2013-10-06:his-dark-materials.html</id><summary type="html">&lt;div class="section" id="review"&gt;
&lt;h2&gt;Review:&lt;/h2&gt;
&lt;div class="figure align-center"&gt;
&lt;a class="reference external image-reference" href="http://tuxcanfly.me/static/images/paradise-lost.jpg"&gt;&lt;img alt="The fall of Luciferìì" src="http://tuxcanfly.me/static/images/paradise-lost.jpg" /&gt;&lt;/a&gt;
&lt;p class="caption"&gt;Gustave Doré, The fall of Luciferìì. Illustration for John Milton’s
“Paradise Lost“ by Gustave Doré, 1866. License: Public Domain&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;/div&gt;
&lt;p&gt;Quote:&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;pre class="literal-block"&gt;
We have to be all those difficult things like cheerful and kind and curious and
patient, and we’ve got to study and think and work hard, all of us, in all our
different worlds, and then we’ll build…&amp;quot; ... &amp;quot;And then what?&amp;quot; said her Dæmon
sleepily &amp;quot;build what?&amp;quot; &amp;quot;The Republic of Heaven.&amp;quot;

-- Chapter 37 The Botanic Garden, Amber Spyglass
&lt;/pre&gt;
&lt;p&gt;It's been about a week since I've finished the last chapter of the series, and
I'm still absolutely floored at what a magnificent journey it has been and
still reeling from the emotional roller-coaster that the last chapters have
been. The series starts of with so many open mysteries and ends them all with
such grace that you can only wonder at it in awe. I'm glad that such a series
exists, that I came to know about it and had the extremely grateful opportunity
to read and enjoy it. I'm a mere mortal and I'm sure I can't do this series
justice by reviewing it, but I shall dare to try anyway.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;His Dark Materials is an epic fantasy trilogy consisting of three books:&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;ul class="simple"&gt;
&lt;li&gt;The Northern Lights&lt;/li&gt;
&lt;li&gt;The Subtle Knife&lt;/li&gt;
&lt;li&gt;The Amber Spyglass&lt;/li&gt;
&lt;/ul&gt;
&lt;div class="section" id="the-northern-lights"&gt;
&lt;h3&gt;The Northern Lights:&lt;/h3&gt;
&lt;p&gt;The story is set in a parallel universe not unlike ours (although in the
beginning of the modern age), but with Dust, dæmons, the Alethiometer, witches,
angels and armoured bears. Lyra and her dæmon, Pantalaimon are off to a great
adventure to the North with the Gyptians where they'll need to rescue children
who have been kidnapped by the Gobblers. On her journey, Lyra encounters the
witches and armoured bears, seeking their help in her task. With courage,
cunning and the help of Iorek Byrnison the armoured bear, she takes on the evil
Gobblers. Towards the end, she has to choose between staying back or following
her father into another universe to seek closure for a friend she betrays
accidentally.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;The action, adventure and mystery in this book make for a gripping narrative
will keep the reader hooked to solve the puzzle. A brief chat between the witch
Serafina Pekkala and the aeronaut Lee Scoresby contrasts the politics of both
sides. The exchange of words between Lyra and her father towards the end throws
light on the book's philosophy.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;/div&gt;
&lt;div class="section" id="the-subtle-knife"&gt;
&lt;h3&gt;The Subtle Knife:&lt;/h3&gt;
&lt;p&gt;Finding herself in a strange new world (Cittàgazze), Lyra wanders and finds
another visitor, Will (from our current universe) and thus begins another
adventure to find Will's father, John Parry who is believed to have travelled
across to another universe. They enter Will's universe and find themselves in
trouble because the Alethiometer gets stolen by one of the members of the
Church and they have to find a certain &amp;quot;Subtle Knife&amp;quot; to get their Alethiometer
back. After a long fight with Knife's owner in Cittàgazze, they manage to get
hold of it and soon discover it's magic - it's a knife that can cut through the
very fabric of time and space to create a portal into another Universe! So, the
children use it and get back their stolen stuff with a clever plan. Lyra also
makes a new friend called Dr Mary Malone whose research into Dark Matter turns
out be similar to Dust. Meanwhile, Lyra's old friend Mr. Scoresby is assisting
Will's father find the children. Unfortunately, also looking for Will and Lyra
is a unit of the Church, headed by Mrs Coulter.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;The second book introduces elements of science-fiction and builds on the
growing tension between the freethinkers headed by Lord Asriel and the Church.
There are a few heartbreaking moments when Lee Scoresby defends against the
Church's army and John Parry meets his son, Will.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;/div&gt;
&lt;div class="section" id="the-amber-spyglass"&gt;
&lt;h3&gt;The Amber Spyglass:&lt;/h3&gt;
&lt;p&gt;We find that Mrs Coulter has kidnapped Lyra and many groups are looking for her
including Will and the armoured bears whom he befriends, Lord Asriel's army and
the Church's army. As is expected, there's a showdown between the three forces,
and the children manage to escape to another universe, Mrs Coulter is captured
by Lord Asriel's army. Meanwhile, Dr Mary Malone crosses into a strange
universe with small elephant-like creatures using wheels in addition to their
limbs. As the children go looking for the world of the dead, we find that the
Church has dispatched a hitman to kill Lyra to prevent a prophecy which would
end the Church's power. Mrs Coulter escapes to the Church, spies on them and
learns of another plan to assasinate Lyra. With the introduction of Metatron,
the Authority's commander, the fate of the battle between Lord Asriel and all
of the Church looms in the balance.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;After an epic battle, we find the children with Dr Mary Malone who tempts them
into falling in love by telling them her story. What follows is an absolutely
amazing sequence recreating the traditional Adam and Eve story - the
temptation, the fall, the realization and acceptance.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;/div&gt;
&lt;/div&gt;
&lt;div class="section" id="conclusion"&gt;
&lt;h2&gt;Conclusion:&lt;/h2&gt;
&lt;p&gt;There are lot of fantasy books and lots of beautiful poems, but in my opinion
none can match the breathtaking mix of fantasy and poetry that is His Dark
Materials. Yes, there are a few loose threads, but I think they are far too
minor to worry about. To crave for a 'happy lived together ever after' ending
is to miss the point of the book - there's no Paradise after all! If you want
one, create it yourself!&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;/div&gt;
</summary><category term="his-dark-materials"></category><category term="fantasy"></category><category term="books"></category></entry><entry><title>The Trial - Franz Kafka</title><link href="http://tuxcanfly.me/the-trial.html" rel="alternate"></link><updated>2013-07-08T23:00:00+05:30</updated><author><name>Javed Khan</name></author><id>tag:tuxcanfly.me,2013-07-08:the-trial.html</id><summary type="html">&lt;div class="section" id="review"&gt;
&lt;h2&gt;Review:&lt;/h2&gt;
&lt;p&gt;The Trial is a wonderful yet depressing book by Franz Kafka which explores the
human condition while telling the story about a mysterious trial endured by a
certain Mr Joseph K who works as a Chief Clerk in a bank.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;One day, Mr K is surprised to find Police in his home, who are there to arrest
him for a crime which they can't reveal - because it's secret. Now, he is faced
with the daunting task of preparing his defence, without knowing any details
about the accusations, or hearing any arguments from the prosecution. Secret
courts, shabby courtrooms located in attics, strange lawyers and even stranger
laws all contribute to the madness that Mr K has to deal with.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;The book plays on the theme of the Condemned Man -  similar to other
existentialist literature like Crime and Punishment by Dostoyevsky and The
Outsider by Albert Camus, but is much more enjoyable because of the bizarre,
crazy and sadistic bureaucracy involved in the courtroom. Subtle allegories
point toward the similarities between the human condition and Mr K's plight.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;4/5 - a pleasure to read.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;/div&gt;
</summary><category term="kafka"></category><category term="books"></category></entry><entry><title>The Metamorphosis - Franz Kafka</title><link href="http://tuxcanfly.me/the-metamorphosis.html" rel="alternate"></link><updated>2013-06-26T22:00:00+05:30</updated><author><name>Javed Khan</name></author><id>tag:tuxcanfly.me,2013-06-26:the-metamorphosis.html</id><summary type="html">&lt;div class="section" id="review"&gt;
&lt;h2&gt;Review:&lt;/h2&gt;
&lt;p&gt;The Metamorphosis (Die Verwandlung) is a novella by Franz Kafka which tells a
bizarre story with a rather mundane conclusion. It's surreal premise and
claustrophobic environment keeps the reader guessing throughout.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;The story is set in an early 20th century Germany city and takes place in the
household of the Mr and Mrs. Samsa who live with their son and daughter -
Gregory and Grete.  Gregory is a hard-working salesman who supports his family,
while the rest of the family members are dependent on him. So far, so good. Now
one fine day, Gregory turns into a weird human-sized bug and what follows is
the turn of events that occur in their household and how Gregory copes with his
newfound cockroach-like body. Doesn't make sense? Well.. too bad for you.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;Now that Mr. Gregory, the cockroach, is incapable of supporting the family,
it's up to his parents and his sister to provide for themselves and also take
care of him. At the end of the story, the sister is shown to have matured and
the parents also seem to have regained their health. I guess the question is -
what was the metamorphosis and what changed?&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;Warning! - The answer might trigger an existential crisis.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;4/5 - would read again&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;/div&gt;
</summary><category term="kafka"></category><category term="books"></category></entry><entry><title>Bitcoin for developers</title><link href="http://tuxcanfly.me/bitcoin-for-developers.html" rel="alternate"></link><updated>2013-05-05T22:00:00+05:30</updated><author><name>Javed Khan</name></author><id>tag:tuxcanfly.me,2013-05-05:bitcoin-for-developers.html</id><summary type="html">&lt;div class="section" id="about"&gt;
&lt;h2&gt;About&lt;/h2&gt;
&lt;p&gt;This was a talk on Bitcoin I presented at Agiliq - April 2013&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;div style="height:60%; width:60%"&gt;
    &lt;script async class="speakerdeck-embed" data-id="5350f0707f4001303c5e22000a1d8ce4" data-ratio="1.33333333333333" src="http://speakerdeck.com/assets/embed.js"&gt;&lt;/script&gt;
&lt;/div&gt;&lt;/div&gt;
</summary><category term="bitcoin"></category><category term="talk"></category></entry><entry><title>Month of FOSS contributions - Apr '13</title><link href="http://tuxcanfly.me/month-of-foss-contributions-apr-13.html" rel="alternate"></link><updated>2013-05-05T21:00:00+05:30</updated><author><name>Javed Khan</name></author><id>tag:tuxcanfly.me,2013-05-05:month-of-foss-contributions-apr-13.html</id><summary type="html">&lt;div class="section" id="about"&gt;
&lt;h2&gt;About&lt;/h2&gt;
&lt;p&gt;Stuff that I contributed to Open Source in Apr '13.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;/div&gt;
&lt;div class="section" id="merchant"&gt;
&lt;h2&gt;Merchant&lt;/h2&gt;
&lt;p&gt;django-merchant is a Django app to accept payments from various payment
processors via Pluggable backends.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;I'm glad to have the chance the contribute to merchant again; I was previously
involved in the design as well as eWay and bitcoin backends.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;I have added a Continuous Integration build for merchant over at &lt;a class="reference external" href="https://travis-ci.org/agiliq/merchant"&gt;Travis&lt;/a&gt;&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;What's more, the &lt;a class="reference external" href="http://merchant.agiliq.com"&gt;demo&lt;/a&gt; is less of an eyesore now; it has been revamped using
bootstrap&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;We received contributions to Braintree, Google Checkout, and eWay backends
which I have reviewed and merged.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;Overall, it’s been a really good month for django-merchant, here's to hoping
this continues.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;div class="figure align-center"&gt;
&lt;a class="reference external image-reference" href="http://tuxcanfly.me/static/images/merchant-progress.png"&gt;&lt;img alt="Merchant Progress" src="http://tuxcanfly.me/static/images/merchant-progress.png" /&gt;&lt;/a&gt;
&lt;p class="caption"&gt;GitHub pulse for django-merchant&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;/div&gt;
&lt;/div&gt;
</summary><category term="foss"></category><category term="contributions"></category></entry><entry><title>Month of FOSS contributions - Mar '13</title><link href="http://tuxcanfly.me/month-of-foss-contributions-mar-13.html" rel="alternate"></link><updated>2013-03-31T21:00:00+05:30</updated><author><name>Javed Khan</name></author><id>tag:tuxcanfly.me,2013-03-31:month-of-foss-contributions-mar-13.html</id><summary type="html">&lt;div class="section" id="about"&gt;
&lt;h2&gt;About&lt;/h2&gt;
&lt;p&gt;Stuff that I contributed to Open Source in Mar '13.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;/div&gt;
&lt;div class="section" id="django"&gt;
&lt;h2&gt;Django&lt;/h2&gt;
&lt;p&gt;I debugged an issue in django &lt;cite&gt;ModelChoiceField&lt;/cite&gt; and &lt;cite&gt;ModelMultipleChoiceField&lt;/cite&gt;
which was causing model forms to be validated even though they weren't changed.
The problem was that &lt;cite&gt;has_changed&lt;/cite&gt; was comparing an &lt;cite&gt;object_id&lt;/cite&gt; or list of
&lt;cite&gt;ids&lt;/cite&gt; with an instance or queryset.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;Even though the fix was a part of another branch, the tests I had proposed were
included in the commit.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;&lt;a class="reference external" href="https://github.com/django/django/commit/3318595c0bfeda9f6bae8aa11dda68647ae55fde"&gt;3318595c&lt;/a&gt;&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;&lt;a class="reference external" href="https://github.com/django/django/pull/660"&gt;Pull request&lt;/a&gt;&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;/div&gt;
&lt;div class="section" id="vimux-django-tests"&gt;
&lt;h2&gt;Vimux-django-tests&lt;/h2&gt;
&lt;p&gt;This is a pet project that I started to make it easier to run individual django
tests from within vim.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;&lt;a class="reference external" href="https://github.com/tuxcanfly/vimux-django-tests"&gt;Vimux-django-tests&lt;/a&gt;&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;/div&gt;
</summary><category term="foss"></category><category term="contributions"></category></entry><entry><title>Logging in Django</title><link href="http://tuxcanfly.me/logging-in-django.html" rel="alternate"></link><updated>2013-03-30T17:00:00+05:30</updated><author><name>Javed Khan</name></author><id>tag:tuxcanfly.me,2013-03-30:logging-in-django.html</id><summary type="html">&lt;div class="section" id="about"&gt;
&lt;h2&gt;About&lt;/h2&gt;
&lt;p&gt;This was a talk I presented at Hyderbad Python meetup - March 2013&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;div style="height:60%; width:60%"&gt;
    &lt;script async class="speakerdeck-embed" data-id="b33f5e2074ec0130286a22000a1f8aa6" data-ratio="1.33333333333333" src="http://speakerdeck.com/assets/embed.js"&gt;&lt;/script&gt;
&lt;/div&gt;&lt;/div&gt;
</summary><category term="django"></category><category term="talk"></category></entry><entry><title>Month of FOSS contributions - Feb '13</title><link href="http://tuxcanfly.me/month-of-foss-contributions-feb-13.html" rel="alternate"></link><updated>2013-02-28T21:00:00+05:30</updated><author><name>Javed Khan</name></author><id>tag:tuxcanfly.me,2013-02-28:month-of-foss-contributions-feb-13.html</id><summary type="html">&lt;div class="section" id="about"&gt;
&lt;h2&gt;About&lt;/h2&gt;
&lt;p&gt;I'm documenting my contributions to FOSS every month from now for two purposes:&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;ul class="simple"&gt;
&lt;li&gt;As a log of my activity&lt;/li&gt;
&lt;li&gt;To serve as a motivation for further participation&lt;/li&gt;
&lt;/ul&gt;
&lt;p&gt;Psst, also for boasting about it, wink wink.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;/div&gt;
&lt;div class="section" id="whoosh"&gt;
&lt;h2&gt;Whoosh&lt;/h2&gt;
&lt;p&gt;While trying to work on django-haystack, I found a bug reported by Zed Shaw
where a search query would crash the search page provided by haystack.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;Upon digging into haystack and whoosh, I found that there's a edge case in the
whoosh query parser where passing a query containg a stop word and negative
filter can raise an error (e.g: the query string &lt;cite&gt;?q=-1&lt;/cite&gt;). I figured out a simple
fix and submitted a pull request which was promptly accepted.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;I was hoping to find something to contribute to haystack and help with the
maintanance, but looks like it will have to wait untill I get some more time.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;&lt;a class="reference external" href="https://bitbucket.org/mchaput/whoosh/commits/362fc2999c8cabc51370f433de7402fafd536ec6"&gt;362fc299&lt;/a&gt;&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;/div&gt;
&lt;div class="section" id="django-browserid"&gt;
&lt;h2&gt;django-browserid&lt;/h2&gt;
&lt;p&gt;I have always been a fan of mozilla and django-browserid looks like the perfect
match for me to contribute towards. I tried out the library by going through
the docs and found it to be a breeze. I was able to improve the docs a bit and
triage a few bugs.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;I have to say people working on this project are very helpful and
understanding. Looking forward to spending more time on this project in the
future.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;&lt;a class="reference external" href="https://github.com/mozilla/django-browserid/commit/f5fc0f124fda1fded862863ef56cab11f23c308d"&gt;f5fc0f12&lt;/a&gt;&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;&lt;a class="reference external" href="https://github.com/mozilla/django-browserid/commit/b9a17a4088211908de2a17a57668a646555f068a"&gt;b9a17a408&lt;/a&gt;&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;/div&gt;
&lt;div class="section" id="conclusion"&gt;
&lt;h2&gt;Conclusion&lt;/h2&gt;
&lt;p&gt;I really enjoyed working on these projects, and I'm looking forward to speding more time to get more
comfortable with them and contributing even more. Here's to bigger, better things!&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;/div&gt;
</summary><category term="foss"></category><category term="contributions"></category></entry><entry><title>Developing Ubuntu Apps for fun and profit</title><link href="http://tuxcanfly.me/pycon-india-2012-talk.html" rel="alternate"></link><updated>2013-02-23T17:00:00+05:30</updated><author><name>Javed Khan</name></author><id>tag:tuxcanfly.me,2013-02-23:pycon-india-2012-talk.html</id><summary type="html">&lt;div class="section" id="about"&gt;
&lt;h2&gt;About&lt;/h2&gt;
&lt;p&gt;This was a talk I presented at PyCon India 2012.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;iframe src="https://docs.google.com/presentation/d/1FCkHcZ8cim0oy58sOcG7xeyL4HKmP4v8xR4_wdnLYxM/embed?start=false&amp;loop=false&amp;delayms=3000" frameborder="0" width="480" height="389" allowfullscreen="true" mozallowfullscreen="true" webkitallowfullscreen="true"&gt;&lt;/iframe&gt;&lt;/div&gt;
</summary><category term="ubuntu"></category><category term="talk"></category></entry><entry><title>Announcing Editorize beta</title><link href="http://tuxcanfly.me/announcing-editorize-beta.html" rel="alternate"></link><updated>2013-01-14T17:00:00+05:30</updated><author><name>Javed Khan</name></author><id>tag:tuxcanfly.me,2013-01-14:announcing-editorize-beta.html</id><summary type="html">&lt;div class="section" id="summary"&gt;
&lt;h2&gt;Summary&lt;/h2&gt;
&lt;p&gt;Editorize summons up your favorite text editor with a global shortcut so that
you can edit your text the way you want it. Close the file and the text
automagically gets pasted in to the text field you were editing.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;Editorize is in beta and needs some bugfixes/cleanup before it can be
considered stable.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;/div&gt;
&lt;div class="section" id="installation"&gt;
&lt;h2&gt;Installation&lt;/h2&gt;
&lt;p&gt;The easiest way to install editorize is by &lt;a class="reference external" href="https://launchpad.net/~tuxcanfly/+archive/editorize"&gt;using the ppa&lt;/a&gt;:&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;div class="highlight"&gt;&lt;pre&gt;sudo apt-add-repository ppa:tuxcanfly/editorize
&lt;/pre&gt;&lt;/div&gt;
&lt;p&gt;After that, updated and install the &lt;cite&gt;editorize&lt;/cite&gt; package:&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;div class="highlight"&gt;&lt;pre&gt;sudo apt-get update
sudo apt-get install editorize
&lt;/pre&gt;&lt;/div&gt;
&lt;p&gt;Source packages are available from the &lt;a class="reference external" href="https://launchpad.net/editorize"&gt;launchpad project page&lt;/a&gt;.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;Now you should be able to launch the app from the start menu / dash or using
the command &lt;cite&gt;editorize&lt;/cite&gt;&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;/div&gt;
&lt;div class="section" id="usage"&gt;
&lt;h2&gt;Usage&lt;/h2&gt;
&lt;p&gt;The default global keyboard shortcut for launching your default text editor is:&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;div class="highlight"&gt;&lt;pre&gt;&amp;lt;Ctrl&amp;gt;&amp;lt;Alt&amp;gt;i
&lt;/pre&gt;&lt;/div&gt;
&lt;p&gt;Both the shortcut and text editor can be customized from the &lt;cite&gt;Preferences&lt;/cite&gt; menu
of the App Indicator.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;Just go to a text input field on any app and use the above keyboard shortcut
and your text editor should pop open. Now enter your text, save and close the
editor. The input text should get copied to the app.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;/div&gt;
&lt;div class="section" id="help-bugs"&gt;
&lt;h2&gt;Help/Bugs:&lt;/h2&gt;
&lt;p&gt;Please report &lt;a class="reference external" href="https://bugs.launchpad.net/editorize"&gt;bugs on launchpad&lt;/a&gt;&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;/div&gt;
</summary><category term="ubuntu"></category><category term="editorize"></category><category term="project"></category></entry><entry><title>Boost your productivity with compiz</title><link href="http://tuxcanfly.me/compiz-productivity.html" rel="alternate"></link><updated>2012-12-15T17:00:00+05:30</updated><author><name>Javed Khan</name></author><id>tag:tuxcanfly.me,2012-12-15:compiz-productivity.html</id><summary type="html">&lt;div class="section" id="summary"&gt;
&lt;h2&gt;Summary&lt;/h2&gt;
&lt;p&gt;Compiz provides powerful window control features which can be used to improve
daily work flow.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;/div&gt;
&lt;div class="section" id="installation"&gt;
&lt;h2&gt;Installation&lt;/h2&gt;
&lt;p&gt;To start off, you'll need to install the following additional packages:&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;div class="highlight"&gt;&lt;pre&gt;compizconfig-settings-manager compiz-plugins-main compiz-plugins-extra
&lt;/pre&gt;&lt;/div&gt;
&lt;div class="warning"&gt;
&lt;p class="first admonition-title"&gt;Warning&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;Before you proceed, you should know that fiddling with compiz is risky and
will probably cause your desktop session to freeze if something goes wrong.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p class="last"&gt;&lt;a class="reference external" href="http://www.ubuntugeek.com/enable-ctrl-alt-backspace-in-ubuntukubuntu-10-04lucid-lynx.html"&gt;Enable XServer Zap&lt;/a&gt; keyboard shortcut and be prepared to use it.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;/div&gt;
&lt;/div&gt;
&lt;div class="section" id="preferences"&gt;
&lt;h2&gt;Preferences&lt;/h2&gt;
&lt;p&gt;Checkout the Preferences options. I prefer the Flat-file configuration backend
as I want to keep all my compiz configuration in a single file and version
control it.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;Make sure you create a backup of your current config using the Export option
before you start.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;Here's my &lt;a class="reference external" href="https://gist.github.com/4296914"&gt;compiz config&lt;/a&gt; if you want to import it.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;/div&gt;
&lt;div class="section" id="commands"&gt;
&lt;h2&gt;Commands&lt;/h2&gt;
&lt;div class="figure align-center"&gt;
&lt;a class="reference external image-reference" href="http://tuxcanfly.me/static/images/commands.gif"&gt;&lt;img alt="Showcasing compiz commands" src="http://tuxcanfly.me/static/images/commands.gif" /&gt;&lt;/a&gt;
&lt;p class="caption"&gt;I've mapped &amp;lt;Super&amp;gt;Return to my terminal (urxvt) and
&amp;lt;Super&amp;gt;e to my editor (gvim)&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;/div&gt;
&lt;p&gt;The Commands plugin gives you a simple way to assign keyboard shortcuts to any
command.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;Figure out your most used commands/apps and assign shortcuts to them. No more
wading your way through menus and searching for apps. Some commands I use:&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;div class="highlight"&gt;&lt;pre&gt;urxvt -&amp;gt; &amp;lt;Super&amp;gt;Return
gvim -&amp;gt; &amp;lt;Super&amp;gt;e
chromium-browser --incognito -&amp;gt; &amp;lt;Shift&amp;gt;&amp;lt;Super&amp;gt;w
nautilus -&amp;gt; &amp;lt;Super&amp;gt;t
gnome-screensaver-command --lock -&amp;gt; &amp;lt;Super&amp;gt;b
&lt;/pre&gt;&lt;/div&gt;
&lt;/div&gt;
&lt;div class="section" id="general"&gt;
&lt;h2&gt;General&lt;/h2&gt;
&lt;a class="reference external image-reference" href="http://tuxcanfly.me/static/images/general.gif"&gt;&lt;img alt="Showcasing general key bindings" class="align-center" src="http://tuxcanfly.me/static/images/general.gif" /&gt;&lt;/a&gt;
&lt;p&gt;I find the key-bindings in this section very useful. For example:&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;div class="highlight"&gt;&lt;pre&gt;Close Window -&amp;gt; &amp;lt;Super&amp;gt;q
Toggle Window Maximizes -&amp;gt; &amp;lt;Super&amp;gt;m
&lt;/pre&gt;&lt;/div&gt;
&lt;p&gt;Combined with Commands plugin above, this configuration allows you to spawn,
close and maximize/restore your windows all with key-bindings!&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;/div&gt;
&lt;div class="section" id="extra-wm-actions"&gt;
&lt;h2&gt;Extra WM Actions&lt;/h2&gt;
&lt;a class="reference external image-reference" href="http://tuxcanfly.me/static/images/extra.gif"&gt;&lt;img alt="Showcasing extra wm actions" class="align-center" src="http://tuxcanfly.me/static/images/extra.gif" /&gt;&lt;/a&gt;
&lt;p&gt;Ever wanted to turn a window fullscreen but couldn't because the app doesn't
allow it?  Want to keep a window on top?&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;Extra WM actions provides key-bindings for these features. The mapping I use:&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;div class="highlight"&gt;&lt;pre&gt;Toggle Fullscreen -&amp;gt; &amp;lt;Supfer&amp;gt;f
&lt;/pre&gt;&lt;/div&gt;
&lt;/div&gt;
&lt;div class="section" id="grid"&gt;
&lt;h2&gt;Grid&lt;/h2&gt;
&lt;a class="reference external image-reference" href="http://tuxcanfly.me/static/images/grid.gif"&gt;&lt;img alt="Showcasing grid plugin" class="align-center" src="http://tuxcanfly.me/static/images/grid.gif" /&gt;&lt;/a&gt;
&lt;p&gt;Grid provides a window tiling feature with intuitive key-bindings. It's great
for people coming from a tiling window manager (like me).&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;/div&gt;
&lt;div class="section" id="desktop-wall-cube"&gt;
&lt;h2&gt;Desktop Wall/Cube&lt;/h2&gt;
&lt;a class="reference external image-reference" href="http://tuxcanfly.me/static/images/desktops.gif"&gt;&lt;img alt="Showcasing desktop wall" class="align-center" src="http://tuxcanfly.me/static/images/desktops.gif" /&gt;&lt;/a&gt;
&lt;p&gt;Both plugins provide an intuitive UI for multiple workspaces and are very
helpful for multitasking.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;I map the Move Left/Right to keys on the home row:&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;div class="highlight"&gt;&lt;pre&gt;Move Left -&amp;gt; &amp;lt;Shift&amp;gt;&amp;lt;Control&amp;gt;&amp;lt;Primary&amp;gt;&amp;lt;Super&amp;gt;j
Move Right -&amp;gt; &amp;lt;Shift&amp;gt;&amp;lt;Control&amp;gt;&amp;lt;Primary&amp;gt;&amp;lt;Super&amp;gt;k
&lt;/pre&gt;&lt;/div&gt;
&lt;/div&gt;
&lt;div class="section" id="conclusion"&gt;
&lt;h2&gt;Conclusion&lt;/h2&gt;
&lt;p&gt;I find compiz's features and customizability very useful and I hope you do too.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;Let me know if you know any useful tips in comments.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;/div&gt;
</summary><category term="compiz"></category></entry></feed>