<?xml version="1.0" encoding="utf-8"?>
<feed xmlns="http://www.w3.org/2005/Atom"><title>Does not compute</title><link href="http://tuxcanfly.me/" rel="alternate"></link><link href="http://tuxcanfly.me/feeds/book-review.atom.xml" rel="self"></link><id>http://tuxcanfly.me/</id><updated>2013-10-19T22:00:00+05:30</updated><entry><title>Kafka on the shore - Haruki Murakami</title><link href="http://tuxcanfly.me/kafka-on-the-shore.html" rel="alternate"></link><updated>2013-10-19T22:00:00+05:30</updated><author><name>Javed Khan</name></author><id>tag:tuxcanfly.me,2013-10-19:kafka-on-the-shore.html</id><summary type="html">&lt;div class="figure align-center"&gt;
&lt;a class="reference external image-reference" href="http://tuxcanfly.me/static/images/kafka-on-the-shore.jpg"&gt;&lt;img alt="Cover Art - Kafka on the shore" src="http://tuxcanfly.me/static/images/kafka-on-the-shore.jpg" /&gt;&lt;/a&gt;
&lt;p class="caption"&gt;Original Book Cover - Kafka on the shore&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;/div&gt;
&lt;div class="section" id="review"&gt;
&lt;h2&gt;Review:&lt;/h2&gt;
&lt;p&gt;Quote:&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;pre class="literal-block"&gt;
Yeah, but if you look at it like that we're all pretty much empty, don't
you think?  You eat, take a dump, do your crummy job for your lousy pay,
and get laid occasionally, if you're lucky. What else is there?

― Haruki Murakami, Kafka on the shore
&lt;/pre&gt;
&lt;p&gt;This is my first Murakami book and I didn't know what to expect. Boy, was I in
for a treat. Kafka's bizzare universe seems to have been waiting for someone to
revive it and Murakami sure looks like a worthy contender. Just like Kafka,
Murakami succeeds in conjuring up a world where things are slightly off and
there's obvious doom awaiting the protagonist. But, Murakami takes it further
and gives it a post-modern touch by adding elements of metaphors, magic,
philosophy and self-references.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;Kafka on the shore begins with a boy called Kafka packing his things and
preparing to run away from his home. He succeeds in reaching another place,
finding a place to live and thus evades the destiny that was awaiting him. Or
has he? He's living at a library with two peculiar characters - a transgender
man called Oshima and his(her?) loner boss called Miss Saeki. Meanwhile back in
Nakano (where Kafka runs away from), we're introduced to a mentally challenged
old man named Nakata who is gifted with the ability to talk to cats. The rest
of the story is all about how Kafka and Nakata's paths slowly but eventually
cross. A curse has been placed on Kafka by his father because of her mother's
sudden departure. Much as Kafka tries to avoid this curse, he seems to stumble
right in the middle of it.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;Fish raining from the sky, Johnnie Walker - the cat eater, Colonel Sanders - the
pimp, the philosophy grad hooker who talks Hegel, the ghost girl, the Entrance
Stone, the Edge of the World, the runaway soldiers. Sounds interesting, right?&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;If I had to condense the meaning I took from the book into one word, it would
be 'Acceptance'. Life is full of sadness - Miss Saeki's lover is brutally
murdered by a mob, Kafka's mother leaves without a word, Oshima is born woman
but lives as a man, Nakata had an accident which turns him into an Idiot; but
we shouldn't cling to these memories, we should put them behind and live - live
and enjoy. There's no point in worrying about the future as well - what's gonna
happen is gonna happen - like with Kafka, we can try and hide from fate, but we
can't avoid it. So we have to accept whatever comes our way, with a smile.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;Life's shit, so what?&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;5/5 - excellent read, might change your perspective on life.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;/div&gt;
</summary><category term="kafka"></category><category term="books"></category></entry><entry><title>Sabriel - Garth Nix</title><link href="http://tuxcanfly.me/sabriel.html" rel="alternate"></link><updated>2013-10-13T16:00:00+05:30</updated><author><name>Javed Khan</name></author><id>tag:tuxcanfly.me,2013-10-13:sabriel.html</id><summary type="html">&lt;div class="figure align-center"&gt;
&lt;a class="reference external image-reference" href="http://tuxcanfly.me/static/images/sabriel-book-cover.jpg"&gt;&lt;img alt="Cover Art - Sabriel" src="http://tuxcanfly.me/static/images/sabriel-book-cover.jpg" /&gt;&lt;/a&gt;
&lt;p class="caption"&gt;Original Book Cover - Sabriel&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;/div&gt;
&lt;div class="section" id="review"&gt;
&lt;h2&gt;Review:&lt;/h2&gt;
&lt;p&gt;Quote:&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;pre class="literal-block"&gt;
&amp;quot;Does the walker choose the path, or the path the walker?”
― Garth Nix, Sabriel
&lt;/pre&gt;
&lt;p&gt;Sabriel is the first book of the Old Kingdom aka the Abhorsen trilogy.  It's a
story about the coming-of-age of a young girl named Sabriel (surprise!).  The
plot is set somewhere in England in a place where the normal and the magical
worlds are divided by the Wall. Sabriel and other members of her family are the
Abhorsens or necromancers who are tasked with keeping the dead actually
dead and not letting them wander out into our living world. Death is the main theme
of the book and is described as another universe where dead souls float away in
a river and cross the various gates. Sabriel's adventure begins when she finds
out that her father has been trapped in one of these gates by the evil
Kerrigor. There are some touching father-daughter moments concerning death.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;The narrative is gripping and keeps your attention, but the plot is unoriginal
and a bit too melodramatic. Hardcore fantasy fans might also be disappointed by
the lack of details and history of the magical elements.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;Somewhat off topic, but the cover-art alone is worth buying this book! The
calm, yet determined expression of Sabriel, with her dark hair melting into the
dark realm of Death, it quite perfectly captures the essence of the story.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;3.5/5 - Overall a good read with some memorable if stereotyped characters.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;/div&gt;
</summary><category term="sabriel"></category><category term="fantasy"></category><category term="books"></category></entry><entry><title>His Dark Materials - Phillip Pullman</title><link href="http://tuxcanfly.me/his-dark-materials.html" rel="alternate"></link><updated>2013-10-06T16:00:00+05:30</updated><author><name>Javed Khan</name></author><id>tag:tuxcanfly.me,2013-10-06:his-dark-materials.html</id><summary type="html">&lt;div class="section" id="review"&gt;
&lt;h2&gt;Review:&lt;/h2&gt;
&lt;div class="figure align-center"&gt;
&lt;a class="reference external image-reference" href="http://tuxcanfly.me/static/images/paradise-lost.jpg"&gt;&lt;img alt="The fall of Luciferìì" src="http://tuxcanfly.me/static/images/paradise-lost.jpg" /&gt;&lt;/a&gt;
&lt;p class="caption"&gt;Gustave Doré, The fall of Luciferìì. Illustration for John Milton’s
“Paradise Lost“ by Gustave Doré, 1866. License: Public Domain&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;/div&gt;
&lt;p&gt;Quote:&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;pre class="literal-block"&gt;
We have to be all those difficult things like cheerful and kind and curious and
patient, and we’ve got to study and think and work hard, all of us, in all our
different worlds, and then we’ll build…&amp;quot; ... &amp;quot;And then what?&amp;quot; said her Dæmon
sleepily &amp;quot;build what?&amp;quot; &amp;quot;The Republic of Heaven.&amp;quot;

-- Chapter 37 The Botanic Garden, Amber Spyglass
&lt;/pre&gt;
&lt;p&gt;It's been about a week since I've finished the last chapter of the series, and
I'm still absolutely floored at what a magnificent journey it has been and
still reeling from the emotional roller-coaster that the last chapters have
been. The series starts of with so many open mysteries and ends them all with
such grace that you can only wonder at it in awe. I'm glad that such a series
exists, that I came to know about it and had the extremely grateful opportunity
to read and enjoy it. I'm a mere mortal and I'm sure I can't do this series
justice by reviewing it, but I shall dare to try anyway.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;His Dark Materials is an epic fantasy trilogy consisting of three books:&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;ul class="simple"&gt;
&lt;li&gt;The Northern Lights&lt;/li&gt;
&lt;li&gt;The Subtle Knife&lt;/li&gt;
&lt;li&gt;The Amber Spyglass&lt;/li&gt;
&lt;/ul&gt;
&lt;div class="section" id="the-northern-lights"&gt;
&lt;h3&gt;The Northern Lights:&lt;/h3&gt;
&lt;p&gt;The story is set in a parallel universe not unlike ours (although in the
beginning of the modern age), but with Dust, dæmons, the Alethiometer, witches,
angels and armoured bears. Lyra and her dæmon, Pantalaimon are off to a great
adventure to the North with the Gyptians where they'll need to rescue children
who have been kidnapped by the Gobblers. On her journey, Lyra encounters the
witches and armoured bears, seeking their help in her task. With courage,
cunning and the help of Iorek Byrnison the armoured bear, she takes on the evil
Gobblers. Towards the end, she has to choose between staying back or following
her father into another universe to seek closure for a friend she betrays
accidentally.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;The action, adventure and mystery in this book make for a gripping narrative
will keep the reader hooked to solve the puzzle. A brief chat between the witch
Serafina Pekkala and the aeronaut Lee Scoresby contrasts the politics of both
sides. The exchange of words between Lyra and her father towards the end throws
light on the book's philosophy.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;/div&gt;
&lt;div class="section" id="the-subtle-knife"&gt;
&lt;h3&gt;The Subtle Knife:&lt;/h3&gt;
&lt;p&gt;Finding herself in a strange new world (Cittàgazze), Lyra wanders and finds
another visitor, Will (from our current universe) and thus begins another
adventure to find Will's father, John Parry who is believed to have travelled
across to another universe. They enter Will's universe and find themselves in
trouble because the Alethiometer gets stolen by one of the members of the
Church and they have to find a certain &amp;quot;Subtle Knife&amp;quot; to get their Alethiometer
back. After a long fight with Knife's owner in Cittàgazze, they manage to get
hold of it and soon discover it's magic - it's a knife that can cut through the
very fabric of time and space to create a portal into another Universe! So, the
children use it and get back their stolen stuff with a clever plan. Lyra also
makes a new friend called Dr Mary Malone whose research into Dark Matter turns
out be similar to Dust. Meanwhile, Lyra's old friend Mr. Scoresby is assisting
Will's father find the children. Unfortunately, also looking for Will and Lyra
is a unit of the Church, headed by Mrs Coulter.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;The second book introduces elements of science-fiction and builds on the
growing tension between the freethinkers headed by Lord Asriel and the Church.
There are a few heartbreaking moments when Lee Scoresby defends against the
Church's army and John Parry meets his son, Will.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;/div&gt;
&lt;div class="section" id="the-amber-spyglass"&gt;
&lt;h3&gt;The Amber Spyglass:&lt;/h3&gt;
&lt;p&gt;We find that Mrs Coulter has kidnapped Lyra and many groups are looking for her
including Will and the armoured bears whom he befriends, Lord Asriel's army and
the Church's army. As is expected, there's a showdown between the three forces,
and the children manage to escape to another universe, Mrs Coulter is captured
by Lord Asriel's army. Meanwhile, Dr Mary Malone crosses into a strange
universe with small elephant-like creatures using wheels in addition to their
limbs. As the children go looking for the world of the dead, we find that the
Church has dispatched a hitman to kill Lyra to prevent a prophecy which would
end the Church's power. Mrs Coulter escapes to the Church, spies on them and
learns of another plan to assasinate Lyra. With the introduction of Metatron,
the Authority's commander, the fate of the battle between Lord Asriel and all
of the Church looms in the balance.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;After an epic battle, we find the children with Dr Mary Malone who tempts them
into falling in love by telling them her story. What follows is an absolutely
amazing sequence recreating the traditional Adam and Eve story - the
temptation, the fall, the realization and acceptance.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;/div&gt;
&lt;/div&gt;
&lt;div class="section" id="conclusion"&gt;
&lt;h2&gt;Conclusion:&lt;/h2&gt;
&lt;p&gt;There are lot of fantasy books and lots of beautiful poems, but in my opinion
none can match the breathtaking mix of fantasy and poetry that is His Dark
Materials. Yes, there are a few loose threads, but I think they are far too
minor to worry about. To crave for a 'happy lived together ever after' ending
is to miss the point of the book - there's no Paradise after all! If you want
one, create it yourself!&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;/div&gt;
</summary><category term="his-dark-materials"></category><category term="fantasy"></category><category term="books"></category></entry><entry><title>The Trial - Franz Kafka</title><link href="http://tuxcanfly.me/the-trial.html" rel="alternate"></link><updated>2013-07-08T23:00:00+05:30</updated><author><name>Javed Khan</name></author><id>tag:tuxcanfly.me,2013-07-08:the-trial.html</id><summary type="html">&lt;div class="section" id="review"&gt;
&lt;h2&gt;Review:&lt;/h2&gt;
&lt;p&gt;The Trial is a wonderful yet depressing book by Franz Kafka which explores the
human condition while telling the story about a mysterious trial endured by a
certain Mr Joseph K who works as a Chief Clerk in a bank.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;One day, Mr K is surprised to find Police in his home, who are there to arrest
him for a crime which they can't reveal - because it's secret. Now, he is faced
with the daunting task of preparing his defence, without knowing any details
about the accusations, or hearing any arguments from the prosecution. Secret
courts, shabby courtrooms located in attics, strange lawyers and even stranger
laws all contribute to the madness that Mr K has to deal with.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;The book plays on the theme of the Condemned Man -  similar to other
existentialist literature like Crime and Punishment by Dostoyevsky and The
Outsider by Albert Camus, but is much more enjoyable because of the bizarre,
crazy and sadistic bureaucracy involved in the courtroom. Subtle allegories
point toward the similarities between the human condition and Mr K's plight.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;4/5 - a pleasure to read.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;/div&gt;
</summary><category term="kafka"></category><category term="books"></category></entry><entry><title>The Metamorphosis - Franz Kafka</title><link href="http://tuxcanfly.me/the-metamorphosis.html" rel="alternate"></link><updated>2013-06-26T22:00:00+05:30</updated><author><name>Javed Khan</name></author><id>tag:tuxcanfly.me,2013-06-26:the-metamorphosis.html</id><summary type="html">&lt;div class="section" id="review"&gt;
&lt;h2&gt;Review:&lt;/h2&gt;
&lt;p&gt;The Metamorphosis (Die Verwandlung) is a novella by Franz Kafka which tells a
bizarre story with a rather mundane conclusion. It's surreal premise and
claustrophobic environment keeps the reader guessing throughout.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;The story is set in an early 20th century Germany city and takes place in the
household of the Mr and Mrs. Samsa who live with their son and daughter -
Gregory and Grete.  Gregory is a hard-working salesman who supports his family,
while the rest of the family members are dependent on him. So far, so good. Now
one fine day, Gregory turns into a weird human-sized bug and what follows is
the turn of events that occur in their household and how Gregory copes with his
newfound cockroach-like body. Doesn't make sense? Well.. too bad for you.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;Now that Mr. Gregory, the cockroach, is incapable of supporting the family,
it's up to his parents and his sister to provide for themselves and also take
care of him. At the end of the story, the sister is shown to have matured and
the parents also seem to have regained their health. I guess the question is -
what was the metamorphosis and what changed?&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;Warning! - The answer might trigger an existential crisis.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;4/5 - would read again&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;/div&gt;
</summary><category term="kafka"></category><category term="books"></category></entry></feed>